Dobromir Marinov

Colchester, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662 mr.d.marinov@gmail.com

https://dmarinov.com/

Personal profile

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional experience. My main programming languages are Python and Java and my research interests lie in reinforcement learning, machine vision and software engineering. I am an EU citizen and I am eligible to work and study in the UK.

Employment

MSX International

Software Engineer (Data science department)

Colchester, United Kingdom

June 2018 - Present

- Building and maintaining machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building microservices.
- Python, R, C++, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Redshift, Exasol, LATEX.

MSX International

Software Developer

- Working in a team developing web applications.
- Java EE, SpringMVC, Liferay 6/7, Oracle, Jboss.
- PL/SQL, Hibernate, Freemarker, Gradle, Selenium.

Colchester, United Kingdom

November 2016 - June 2018

StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites.
- PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

July 2016 - September 2016

Education

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer) (BSc) October 2016 - September 2019 (Expected)

Capstone Project: Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

Relevant Modules:

- Software Engineering.
- Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Evolutionary Computation and Generic Programming.
- Advanced Programming.

Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

- Learning Under Different Training and Testing Distributions.
- Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the Modelling and Analysis of Complex Systems.
- Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks in Analytics.

High School of Mathematics

Secondary education

- Program with extensive study of Mathematics, English and IT.
- Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Awards and Certificates

Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the final year student who achieves the highest degree mark.

Tech Industry Gold Certificate of Recognition

Tech Partnership Degrees

• Nominated by the University of Essex for outstanding academic achievements and awarded by the Tech Partnership Degrees.

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Certificate of attainment

Information Security

Certificate of attainment

The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the 2nd year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

September 2011 - June 2016

Colchester, United Kingdom

 $July\ 2019$

London, United Kingdom

June 2019

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2019

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2019

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2018

K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

University of Essex

 $Colchester,\ United\ Kingdom$

September 2017

• Awarded to the top 4 first year students, in CSEE, with the best overall year mark.

Award of Excellence

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

High School of Mathematics

June 2016

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

StangaOne1 Academy

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

Web Development Basics

January 2016 - May 2016

• PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML 5, CSS 3.

Extracurricular activity

Course Representative (1st and 2nd year)

Colchester, United Kingdom

University of Essex

October 2016 – June 2018

• Representing and supporting students on the course and in the department.

German 1 and 2 University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom

October 2016 - April 2018

Colchester Zoo Volunteer

Colchester, United Kingdom

University of Essex

July 2017 - September 2017

HackEssex 2017

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2017

University of Essex24 hours hackathon.

• Eye tracking software integrated into a website.

• Selected as one of the top 3 best projects out of 20 competing.

UNESCO Project for an educational game

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

University of Essex

January 2015 - September 2016

• Main programmer.

• Made using Unity.